Guide to the Irish Repertory Theatre Records AIA.080
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV. Financial and Legal Records, 1989-2010; 2.5 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes
  This series documents legal proceedings in which the IRT was involved, financial audits, and renovation of the IRT in 1995. This series consists of paper material and includes correspondence, contracts, court documents, audits, blueprints, and the IRT's by-laws and certificate of incorporation. Legal proceedings documented in this series include suits brought by the IRT against producer Robert Macken regarding his production of video recordings of The Irish...and How They Got That Way and Fathers to Daughters, and a suit brought by Charles Nelson Reilly against producer Michael Alden regarding Save It for the Stage: The Life of Reilly. The financial materials document the production of The Irish...and How They Got That Way and its 1997-1998 tour in New York City and Boston, Massachusetts; production budgets and box office totals for other IRT productions; and annual IRT audits. Material regarding the IRT's renovation include correspondence with the architect and blueprints detailing the renovation.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Two folders in this series are protected under the attorney work-product doctrine. They was separated from the collection in March 2018 pending a decision regarding its inclusion in the collection.
  - Audits, 1990-2002 (Box 26, Folder 12-15, Box 27, Folder 1-7)
  - By-laws and certificate of incorporation, 1989-1992 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Fathers to Daughters, 1999-2000
    - Paper (Box 27, Folder 9-12, Box 28, Folder 1-6)
    - Video (Box 33, Cassette 080.0017)
  - Grant application, 2010 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Insurance claims, 1997-1998 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - The Irish…And How They Got That Way, 1999-2000
    - Paper (Box 28, Folder 9-19)
    - Electronic Records, TW_AIA_080_ER_206
  - Macken, Bob, 1998-2002 (Box 28, Folder 20-21, Box 29, Folder 1-12, Box 30, Folder 1-11, Box 42, Folder 1-2)
    Material in box 42 is restricted.
  - 132-134 West 22nd Street, 1994-2010 (Box 31, Folder 1-2, Box Shared Tamiment 003, Folder 6, Flat-file-folder 5)
  - Reilly, Charles Nelson -- Save It for the Stage, 2000-2002 (Box 31, Folder 3-5)
  - State of New York Department of Law, 1990-1997 (Box 31, Folder 6-8)
- Series V. Archived Websites, September 2019-ongoing; 4 websites in 4 archived website.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of web.ovationtix.com/trs/cal/32325, irishrepertorytheatre.passgallery.com, and irishrep.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored.
  In 2023, YouTube URLs were changed to better capture the videos on the channel.
  Irishrep.org is the website of the Irish Repertory Theatre. The website contains information on current and past productions, script submission series, and membership programs.
  The Irish Repertory Theatre YouTube channel features videos of trailers for upcoming performances at the theater related to Irish and Irish-American works, interviews with actors and directors, gala performances, and their #TheShowMustGoOnline series created during the COVID-19 pandemic. The Irish Rep web presence also includes a photo gallery from opening night celebrations and fundraising events.